georgiastandards.org 2015-03-22

# Privacy Policy

**Georgia Department of Education Privacy Statement  
Last Updated October, 2004**  

The Georgia Department of Education ("GaDOE") is committed to protecting your privacy. You can visit most pages on our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this privacy statement explains data collection and use in those situations. This privacy statement only applies to georgiastandards.org; it does not apply to other online or offline GaDOE sites, products or services. Please read the complete GaDOE privacy statement. 

**Collection of your Personal Information**

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you. Generally, this information is requested when you are registering before entering a contest, ordering e-mail newsletters, joining a limited-access premium site, signing up for an event or training, or when purchasing and/or registering GaDOE products. Personal information collected by GaDOE websites often is limited to e-mail address, language, country or location, but may include other information when needed to provide a service you requested. 

For example: If you choose a service or transaction that requires payment, such as making a purchase in the Shop area of the website, we will request personal information necessary for billing and/or shipping, such as: name, address, telephone number, and credit card number. 

When you buy and install a new product, we may ask you to register your purchase electronically. We keep this registration information on file with any information you've already given us on previous visits to our website. 

The GaDOE also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the GaDOE. 

The GaDOE also collects information about which pages our customers visit within georgiastandards.org This site visitation data is identified only by a unique ID number, and it is linked with personal information provided by the user. 

**Use of your Personal Information  
**  
We use your personal information for the following purposes: 

To ensure our site is relevant to your needs. To deliver services, such as newsletters, events, training or software that you request or purchase. To help us create and publish content most relevant to you. To alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new services from GaDOE, if you so request. To allow you access to limited-entry areas of our site as appropriate. We will merge site-visitation data with anonymous demographic information for research purposes, and we may use this information in aggregate to provide more relevant content. In some limited-entry sections of GaDOE, with your approval, we will combine site-visitation data with your personal information in order to provide you with personalized content. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, answering customer questions about products or services, sending postal mail and processing event registration. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. 

GaDOE may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on GaDOE or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of GaDOE and its family of websites, or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of GaDOE employees, users of GaDOE products or services, or members of the public. 

Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which GaDOE or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. GaDOE abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. 

**Control of your Personal Information**

When you register, or otherwise give us personal information, GaDOE will not share that information with third parties without your permission, other than for the limited exceptions already listed. It will only be used for the purposes stated above. 

Registering also allows you to tell us how or whether you want GaDOE to communicate with you. 

GaDOE may send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical service or security issues related to a product or service you requested, or confirming you requested a product or service. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered an essential part of the service you have chosen. 

**Access to your Personal Information**

We will provide you with the means to ensure that your personal information is correct and current. 

If you register on a GaDOE or subscribe to a newsletter, you can review and edit your personal information at the User Information tab within GaDOE. 

**Security of your Personal Information**

GaDOE is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide in computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit sensitive information (such as a credit card number) over the internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

**Protection of Children's Personal Information**

GaDOE is intended for business use and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children. 

**Use of Cookies**

When someone visits the site, a cookie is placed on the customer's machine (if the customer accepts cookies) or is read if the customer has visited the site previously. One use of cookies is to assist in the collection of the site visitation statistics described above. 

**Enforcement of this Privacy Statement**

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact GaDOE by e-mail. 

**Changes to this Statement**

GaDOE will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this statement, GaDOE will notify you by placing prominent notice on the website. 

**Contact Information**

GaDOE welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement, please contact us by e-mail, or postal mail. 

GaDOE Privacy   
Georgia Department of Education  
205  Jesse Hill Jr. Drive SE  
Atlanta, GA 30334
